Preliminary Guide to the Thomas Chapin Papers, 1870s-1999 (bulk 1979-1999)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Thomas Chapin papers 1870s-1999, bulk 1979-1999
Chapin, Thomas
84.9 linear feet Extent: 28,117 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00211
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Also, some of the materials in this collection are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use and/or are housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Thomas Chapin Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift and purchase in 1999 and 2001-2003.
Biographical Note
Jazz saxophonist/flutist and composer (b. 1957 d. 1998) from Connecticut. Musical director of Lionel Hampton's orchestra and then leader of and participant in other ensembles, including his own trio.
Collection Overview
The collection (100 items, 2.5 linear feet; dated 1979-1998) contains audio cassettes and compositions by Thomas Chapin, as well as clippings, programs, memorial messages, and other items about him. Technical Services staff may need to make use copies of audio cassettes before use. No container list was created for this accession. (99-355)
The addition to the collection (60 items, 2.5 linear feet; dated 1981-1999) includes published materials on Chapin or featuring his music. There are publicity materials; scrapbook items, such as programs or clippings; articles about Chapin from the internet and elsewhere; copies of original scores; compact discs; phonograph records; genealogical information, and other biographical information about him and his trio. Technical Services staff may need to make use copies of sound recordings before use. No container list was created for this accession. (99-0467)
The addition to the collection (15300 items, 29.40 linear feet; dated 1870s-1998, bulk 1980-1997) comprises primarily correspondence; financial records; scrapbooks, graphic materials (98 color photographs, 1 color slide, 6 black-and-white photographs, 24 black-and-white negatives, 17 contact sheets, 1 print, 1 watercolor, and 2 chalk drawings), posters, and other materials detailing Chapin's musical career, especially performances of the Chapin Trio; notebooks and appointment books; and musical scores by Chapin and others. Also includes recordings on 17 reel-to-reel tapes, 8 CDs, and 5 audiocassette tapes of performances by Chapin and others; 3 electronic computer files; and 24 small musical instruments of plastic and metal. (01-0157)
The addition (2002-0281 and 2003-0125; 12,657 items, 50.5 linear feet) consists primarily of studio and demo recordings of Chapin's music on audiocassette, vinyl, and reel-to-reel tape. Also contains a number of collages by Chapin, documenting another of his forms of expression; personal items, especially photographs and correspondence, reflecting his close relationships with family and friends; videos and film reels of recording sessions, tours, and other events, including Chapin's memorial service; sheet music and music books; clothing and hats; 3 hand instruments; performance posters; and business items.
Subject Headings
Chapin, Thomas; Thomas Chapin Trio; Jazz; Music -- Performance; Musicians -- Correspondence; Jazz -- Scores; Jazz musicians -- United States; Audiotapes; Audiocassettes; Sound recordings; Videocassettes; Machine-readable records; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Color slide; Contact sheets; Black-and-white negatives; Collages; Musical instruments; Scrapbooks; Posters; Scores; Clippings; Phonograph records; Floppy disk; CD-ROM
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2001-0157
  - Contents of box 1: (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, (7 folders) (Box 1)
    - Business Cards/Addresses (Box 1)
    - Quotations/Notes (Box 1)
    - Thomas Chapin Trio History (Box 1)
  - Contents of box 2: (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence during Chapin's illness/death, (6 folders) (Box 2)
    - Donations to Chapin/Memorial Service (Box 2)
  - Contents of box 3: (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, (8 folders) (Box 3)
  - Contents of box 4: (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, (4 folders)
      - Correspondence from Terri, (6 folders) (Box 4)
  - Contents of box 5: (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, (10 folders) (Box 5)
  - Contents of box 6: (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, (9 folders) (Box 6)
    - Japan-Fax (Box 6)
    - Misc.-Fax, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Labels (Box 6)
  - Contents of box 7: (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, (8 folders) (Box 7)
    - Donation Information (Box 7)
    - Addresses (Box 7)
  - Contents of box 8: (Box 8)
    - Health Insurance/Medical Records, (7 folders) (Box 8)
    - Taxes/Receipts 1995, (1-5 of 8 folders) (Box 8)
  - Contents of box 9: (Box 9)
    - Taxes/Receipts 1995, (6-8 of 8 folders) (Box 9)
    - 1996 Taxes, (5 folders) (Box 9)
    - [Loose Material: Touring Information and Financial Records], (4 folders) (Box 9)
  - Contents of box 10: (Box 10)
    - Correspondence
      - Musicians' letters (Box 10)
      - Notebook, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - [Tours/Engagements/Events], (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - [Reviews/Items about Chapin] (Box 10)
    - [Knitting Factory European Tour] (Box 10)
    - [Thomas Chapin, Alive, CD Box Set] (Box 10)
    - [Loose Material: Touring Information and Financial Material] (Box 10)
    - Banff Centre (Box 10)
  - Contents of box 11: (Box 11)
    - Jazz Donau (Box 11)
    - [Loose Material: Tours/Engagements], (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Jazz Festival Directory, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Chapin Contracts (Box 11)
    - Mailing lists, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Contents of box 12: (Box 12)
    - Contacts (Box 12)
    - [Loose Material] (Box 12)
    - Calendars, (4 folders) (Box 12)
    - Notebook, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Engagement Book (Box 12)
    - [Cassette Tape: Debut, Jerry Waldon] (Box 12)
  - Contents of box 13: (Box 13)
    - Musicians (Box 13)
    - Edward's Book (Box 13)
    - Plaque, Duke University (Box 13)
    - TDC, Music Tribute Archives, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - TDC, Misc./Collage Items (Box 13)
    - Music
      - Japanese Music, (2 folders) (Box 13)
      - Alto/Flute (Box 13)
      - Flamenco and Alborada Latin (Box 13)
  - Contents of box 14: (Box 14)
    - Trio Booklet Project (Box 14)
    - Bio., Ron Matthews and Ray Drummond, Quartet Players with Thomas (Box 14)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, (7 folders) (Box 14)
    - TDC Collage Items and Misc. (Box 14)
    - Music
      - Thomas Chapin (Box 14)
      - Armen Donelian (Box 14)
      - Avantango (Box 14)
      - Andy Jaffe (Box 14)
      - Michael Jeffery Stevens (Box 14)
  - Contents of box 15: (Box 15)
    - Music
      - Satie-Gymnopedies/Shumann-Kindeszenen (Box 15)
      - Junkman's Obligato/Robert Myer's Fantasy Duo (Box 15)
      - Thomas (Box 15)
      - Bozzi Brazil (Box 15)
      - Musillami, Wallach (Box 15)
      - Royal Hartigan, Peggy Stern (Box 15)
    - Poems: Vernon Frazer (Box 15)
    - Photographs of Chapin, (5 folders) (Box 15)
    - Items about Chapin, (5 folders) (Box 15)
  - Contents of box 16: (Box 16)
    - Items about Chapin, (4 folders) (Box 16)
    - Photographs of Chapin (Box 16)
    - Scrapbook (Box 16)
  - Contents of box 17: (Box 17)
    - Scrapbooks (Box 17)
  - Contents of box 18: (Box 18)
    - Scrapbooks (Box 18)
  - Contents of box 19: (Box 19)
    - Scrapbooks (Box 19)
  - Contents of box 20: (Box 20)
    - Scrapbook (Box 20)
    - Scrapbook, 1992-1995, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - [Loose Material: Appearances/Items about Chapin], (3 folders) (Box 20)
  - Contents of box 21: (Box 21)
    - Receipts
      - CDs/Tapes (Box 21)
      - Postage (Box 21)
      - Photography (Box 21)
      - Music Expenses (Box 21)
    - [Telephone Bills] (Box 21)
    - [Bank Statements] (Box 21)
    - [Credit Card Statements] (Box 21)
    - [Misc. Receipts/Financial Records], (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - [Bank Statements] (Box 21)
    - [Telephone Bills] (Box 21)
  - Contents of box 22: (Box 22)
    - [Misc. Receipts] (Box 22)
    - [Misc. Bills] (Box 22)
    - Medical: Unpaid Invoices (Box 22)
    - Medical: Paid Invoices (Box 22)
    - Music: Royalty Statements (Box 22)
    - [Prescription Receipts] (Box 22)
    - [Bank Statements] (Box 22)
    - [Misc. Receipts] (Box 22)
    - [Tax Records 1987] (Box 22)
    - [Misc. Financial Records] (Box 22)
    - Receipts 1988 (Box 22)
    - Thomas Chapin: Recording Session, June-July 1988: Receipts etc., (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - [1989 Tax Return/1990 Tax Figures] (Box 22)
  - Contents of box 23: (Box 23)
    - [1989 Taxes], (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - 1991 Taxes, (3 folders) (Box 23)
    - [Misc. Financial Records], (5 folders) (Box 23)
  - Contents of box 24: (Box 24)
    - 1989 Tax Receipts, (4 folders) (Box 24)
    - 1992 Receipts, (4 folders) (Box 24)
    - 1992 Taxes (Box 24)
    - 1994 Taxes, (3 folders) (Box 24)
  - Contents of box 25: (Box 25)
    - 1994 Taxes, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - [Printed Material: Magazines], (4 folders) (Box 25)
    - [Sheet music], (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - Contents of box 26: (Box 26)
    - [Blank Postcards] (Box 26)
    - [Printed Material: Knitting Factory] (Box 26)
    - Printed Material: Festival Programs], (4 folders) (Box 26)
    - [Printed Material: Magazines/Newsletters/Catalogs]
      - Windplayer, (2 folders) (Box 26)
      - Downbeat (Box 26)
  - Contents of box 27: (Box 27)
    - [Printed Material: Magazines/Newsletters/Catalogs Cont.]
      - Downbeat, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - Saxophone Journal (Box 27)
      - Flute Journal (Box 27)
      - Jazz (Box 27)
      - Andover Bulletin (Box 27)
      - Jazziz (Box 27)
      - Swing Journal, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - Misc. Magazines (Box 27)
  - Contents of box 28: (Box 28)
    - [Printed Material: Magazines/Newsletters/Catalogs cont.]
      - Misc. Magazines, (2 folders) (Box 28)
      - Misc. Newsletters, (2 folders) (Box 28)
      - Misc. Catalogs, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - [Misc. Printed Material] (Box 28)
    - [Printed Material: Amtrak] (Box 28)
  - Contents of box 29: (Box 29)
    - [Manuscript, poems] (Box 29)
    - Re: Heart Arrhythmia, from which Thomas suffered (Box 29)
    - [Financial Records: Misc. Receipts etc.], (1-7 of 22 folders) (Box 29)
  - Contents of box 30: (Box 30)
    - [Financial Records: Misc. Receipts etc. cont.], (8-18 of 22 folders) (Box 30)
  - Contents of box 31: (Box 31)
    - [Financial Records: Misc. Receipts etc. cont.], (19-22 of 22 folders) (Box 31)
    - Tax Returns 1984 (Box 31)
    - Misc. Papers, Music, etc. on Thomas Chapin's Music Stand in "Music Room" at time of death - 2/13/97, (3 folders) (Box 31)
    - Music
      - Doug Miller Arranged; TDC Big Band Arrangement: Zemzem (Box 31)
      - Doug Miller Arranged; TDC Big Band Arrangement: The Present (Box 31)
  - Contents of box 32: (Box 32)
    - Music cont.
      - TDC Composition Books-unpublished (Box 32)
      - TDC Early '80s Compositions (Box 32)
      - Others' Compositions (Box 32)
      - Big Band Arrangement for Bebe (Hermeto Pascoal); Radius (Thomas Chapin) (Box 32)
      - Misc. Hand-Original Notes/Compositions (Box 32)
      - Thomas' Music (Box 32)
      - TDC Compositions: Trio, Quartet, Spirits Groups (Box 32)
      - TDC Big Band Arrangement of Brazilian Carinhosa (Played with Hamp) (Box 32)
      - TDC's Arrangement, One Man Blues w/ Hamp (Box 32)
      - Thomas Chapin Trio plus Brass (Box 32)
      - TDC Early Compositions (Box 32)
    - [Professional Correspondence] (Box 32)
    - 1999 KF Boxed Notes (Box 32)
  - Contents of box 33: (Box 33)
    - Music
      - Conga Sessions with Louis (Box 33)
      - TDC Original Tunes: Pre-Trio Music: Mostly Spirits Rebellious Music (Brazilian Rhythms) and Quartet from late '70s, early '80s (Box 33)
      - Tom's solo to Sans Souci played at Duke (Box 33)
      - Thomas' Music Misc. (Box 33)
      - [Misc. Music] (Box 33)
    - Genealogy: Thomas Dufree Chapin (Box 33)
    - Mailing list [1992], (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - [Items about Chapin/Events/Engagements], (4 folders) (Box 33)
    - [Misc. Material: Coin Collections], (1 of 4 folders) (Box 33)
  - Contents of box 34: (Box 34)
    - [Misc. Material: Coin collections cont.], (2-4 of 4 folders) (Box 34)
    - [Items about Chapin/Events/Engagements etc.], (7 folders) (Box 34)
  - Contents of box 35: (Box 35)
    - [Misc. Music], (3 folders) (Box 35)
    - [Name Tags] (Box 35)
    - [Plastic Bag and Guinness Sticker] (Box 35)
    - Materials from inside book by Vernon Frazer, A Slick Set of Wheels, cataloged separately [see list below] (Box 35)
    - [Separation sheet for computer disk 001 removed from box 7. Contents migrated to Special Collections Server. A disk directories log exists. Contact Research Services for Access.] (Box 35)
    - Thomas Chapin Trio: Track sheets, notes, setups: Q 22802: 1996 July 29 [Material accompanying reel-to-reel tapes listed below] (Box 35)
    - Compact Discs, Chapin
      - Inversions, Thomas Chapin and Borah Berman, (2 CD's) (Box 35)
      - Radius, Thomas Chapin (Box 35)
      - Menagerie Dreams, Thomas Chapin Trio (Box 35)
    - Compact Discs Featuring Chapin
      - Pass the Ammo, Machine Gun (Box 35)
      - Double Band Overlays, Ned Rothenberg (Box 35)
      - President for Life, Vandoorn (Box 35)
    - Cassettes
      - Forgotten Game, Thomas Chapin, (2 cassettes) (Box 35)
      - Other Chapin Cassettes, (2 cassettes) (Box 35)
    - Quarklmmedia 1.02 CD-ROM, (2 copies) (Box 35)
  - Contents of box 36: (Box 36)
    - Music
      - Non-Chapin Compositions of Other Musicians: Standards and Others: Hermeto Pascoal, Roland Kirk, Coltrane etc. (Box 36)
      - Flamenco and Alborada Latina (Box 36)
      - One Man Blues (Box 36)
      - Music: Kahn (Box 36)
      - David Lahm Project, (2 folders) (Box 36)
      - Music: Ray Drummond (Box 36)
    - Frazer, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Sky Piece Liner Notes (Box 36)
    - [Items about Chapin], (2 folders) (Box 36)
  - Contents of box 37: (Box 37)
    - Misc. Material, (3 folders) (Box 37)
    - [Items about Chapin/Obituaries/Engagements], (4 folders) (Box 37)
    - [Healthcare Material] (Box 37)
    - [Receipts 1990-1991] (Box 37)
    - Misc. Papers, Music, etc. on Thomas Chapin's Stand in "Music Room" at Time of Death, 2/13/97, (2 folders) (Box 37)
    - Music
      - Zemzem (Box 37)
      - The Present (Box 37)
  - Contents of box 38: (Box 38)
    - Music
      - TDC Early '80s Compositions, (2 folders) (Box 38)
      - TDC Compositions: Trio, Quartet, Spirits Groups (Box 38)
      - Misc. Hand-Original Notes/Compositions Pre-Trio (Box 38)
      - Big Band Arrangement for Bebe (Hermeto Pascoal); Radius (Thomas Chapin) (Box 38)
      - Others' Compositions (Box 38)
      - TDC Early Compositions (Box 38)
      - TDC Original Tunes: Pre-Trio Music: Mostly Spirits Rebellious Music (Brazilian Rhythms, Late '70s and Quartet from the Early '80s) (Box 38)
    - [Items about Chapin/Events/Engagements] (Box 38)
    - Mailing Lists (Box 38)
    - Misc. Material (Box 38)
  - Contents of box 39: (Box 39)
    - Small Musical Instruments, metal and plastic (Box 39)
  - Contents of oversize box 40: (Box 40)
    - Small Musical Instruments, metal and plastic (Box 40)
  - Contents of oversize box 41: (Box 41)
    - [Poster] (Box 41)
    - [Misc. Photos] (Box 41)
    - [Original Art, including a print, a watercolor, and chalk drawings], (4 folders) (Box 41)
    - TDC Early '80s Compositions (Box 41)
    - [Stock certificates for tobacco and cigarettes in the Congo (in French); other stock certificates in various companies in the U.S.; tax certificates on liquor, U.S., 1870s-1880s] (Box 41)
    - [Printed Material: Misc. Magazines] (Box 41)
    - [Copy of pen and marker drawing of Chapin.] (Box 41)
  - Contents of oversize box 42: (Box 42)
    - Thomas Chapin Original Music (Mostly Quartet) Sent to Paul Jeffrey for 1999 January 29 TDC Tribute: Misc. Comp. plus One Man Blues for Small Band; Plus Oracle, Lens, and Fallen Angel--Unperformed Original Woodwind Pieces (Box 42)
    - Zasis (Box 42)
    - [For Robbie Kaplan] Zazis, Improv Group (after 1975), (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - [Posters/Program] (Box 42)
  - Contents of oversize box 43: (Box 43)
    - [Misc. Material: Correspondence] (Box 43)
    - [Events/Albums] (Box 43)
    - Photo Album, Thomas Chapin Trio, Tondela, Portugal (Box 43)
    - Calendars, 1984, 1987, 1994, 1995 (Box 43)
  - Contents of oversize box 44: (Box 44)
    - Music
      - Tom's Solo for Sans Souci played at Duke (Box 44)
      - Cat's Paw (Box 44)
      - Roland Kirk Arrangement by Thomas Chapin (Box 44)
      - From Bechet, Byas, and Fats: R. Kirk Music Arranged by T.C. (Box 44)
      - Thomas Chapin Trio and Bass, (3 folders) (Box 44)
  - Contents of oversize box 45: (Box 45)
    - Posterboards, Free Concert of Trio at Kampo, [1992] (Box 45)
    - [Posters, Thomas Chapin Trio CD Cover, Nightbird Song/ Misc. Poems] (Box 45)
  - Contents of oversize folder:
    - Posters, (4) (Box 45)
  - Reel-to-Reel tapes recorded by Thomas Chapin Trio
    - Q22803: 1. Untitled Th 1; 2. Untitled Th 2, 1996 July 29 (Reel 1)
    - Q22804: 1. Don't Mind if I Do A) Insert Piece; 2.Don't Mind if I Do, 1996 July 29 (Reel 2)
    - Q22805: 1. Essouria; 2. Essouria, 1996 July 29 (Reel 3)
    - Q22806: 1. Essouria Insert; 2. The Unamable, 1996 July 29 (Reel 4)
    - Q22807: 1. The Unamable; 2) Out and About Pieces see 1, 1996 July 29 (Reel 5)
    - Q22808: 1. Pet Serpent; 2. Ask Me Now, 1996 July 29 (Reel 6)
    - Q22809: 1. Ask Me Now; 2. Ticket to Ride, 1996 July 29 (Reel 7)
    - Q22810: 1. Nightbird; 2. Nightbird; 3. Improv #2, 1996 July 29 (Reel 8)
    - Q22811: 1. Cliff Island; 2. Aeolus; 3. Improv #1, 1996 July 29 (Reel 9)
    - Q22839: 1. Alphaville, 1996 July 29 (Reel 10)
    - Q22840: 1. Roaringesque; 2. Roaring Inserts, 1996 July 30 (Reel 11)
    - Q22834: 1. Flute Solo Aeolus 1+2, 3+4, 1996 July 30 (Reel 12)
    - Q22841: 1. Ticket to Ride; 2. Pet Scorpion, 1996 July 30 (Reel 13)
    - Q22842: 1. Nightbird Th2 Solo Section; 2. The Unnamable Th 2, 1996 July 30 (Reel 14)
    - Q22833: 1. Alphaville Th3; 2. Aeolus Th2, 1996 July 30 (Reel 15)
    - Q22832: 1. Changes 2 Tires Th1; 2. Changes 2 Tires, 1996 July 30 (Reel 16)
    - Q22831: 1. Essounia; 2. Hit the Road Jack; 3. Alto Solo; 4. Poem, 1996 July 30 (Reel 17)
- Accessions 2002-0281 and 2003-0125
  Audio-visual materials may be copied only with donor's permission. Also, journals in boxes 11-14 require donor permission to use until Jan. 1, 2025.
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, [1987-1995] (Box 1)
      Personal correspondence from Terri.
    - Sheet Music by Chapin (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Pollution Solutions Company Brochures (Box 2)
      Includes information on air and water filter systems.
    - [Loose Desk Items]
      - Doctor's Contact Information (Box 2)
      - Copies of Foreign Currency (Box 2)
      - Take-Out Menus (Box 2)
      - [Miscellaneous Plastic Items] (Box 2)
    - Sufi Study Materials (Box 2)
    - Business Cards (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Notecards from Rolodex (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
      Includes greeting cards, postcards and letters between Thomas and Terri.
    - Book of Chapin's Friends' Words and Sentiments (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Instruments (Box 4)
      Three hand instruments belonging to Chapin that were demonstrated in Terri's film The Music Man.
  - Contents of Box 5A: (Box 5A)
    - Special Caps Thomas Wore (Box 5A)
      Includes hair night cap and batik cloth sometimes worn around Chapin's neck and head.
  - Contents of Box 5B: (Box 5B)
    - Clothing, including gaucho hat (Box 5B)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Book of Friends' Sentiments for Thomas and Terri's Wedding (Box 6)
    - Guest Book from Remembering Thomas, a Memorial Service. (Box 6)
    - [Things Collected During Travel] (Box 6)
      Includes receipts, business cards, postcards and airplane tickets.
    - Correspondence, [1988-1999] (Box 6)
      Includes handmade greeting cards and notes between Thomas and Terri.
    - Love for Thomas (Box 6)
      A collection of notes to Chapin from his friends.
    - Guest Book from Chapin's Funeral, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Lao Tzu/Tao Teh Ching (Box 6)
      A book on Asian religion.
    - Rock (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    [Audio materials may be copied only with donor's permission.]
    - Audio Cassette Tapes (Box 7)
      Includes Knitting Factory Tour, 1991 and Life at Newport, 1995.
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Audio Cassette Tapes, 1996 (Box 8)
      Includes Diva, Haywire, and Geek Gawkin'.
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Audio Cassette Tapes (Box 9)
      Includes Night Bird Song and Sky Piece.
  - Contents of Box 10: (Box 10)
    [Video materials may be copied only with donor's permission.]
    - [Music Reviews]
      - You Don't Know Me Review, Jazztimes (Box 10)
      - Haywire Review 1997, Wire (Box 10)
    - [Miscellaneous Written Music and Notes] (Box 10)
    - Personal Travel Photographs
      - Morocco, 1996 (Box 10)
      - Portugal (Box 10)
    - [Loose Materials] (Box 10)
      Contains correspondence and letters from Dennis Capodestria.
    - Videocassettes
      - Thomas Chapin Trio, 1992 June 23 (Box 10)
      - Litchfield Jazz, August 1997 (Box 10)
        Thomas' last full concert while sick.
      - The Thomas Chapin Tribute: The Knitting Factory, New York City 1997 Nov. 23 (Box 10)
    - Foreign Currencies (Box 10)
      Folder includes a lock of hair.
  - Contents of Box 11: (Box 11)
    [Restricted: Donor's permission required before use until 1/1/2025.]
    - Thomas' Sketch Books (Box 11)
      Books include drawings and writings done while Chapin was in the hospital.
    - Journals, 1994 (Box 11)
      Includes loose materials from journals such as business cards, post cards, and correspondence from Namibia.
  - Contents of Box 12: (Box 12)
    - Journals (Box 12)
      Includes newspaper clippings, Chapin's poetry, postcards, match books, and other loose materials.
    - Correspondence Between Chapin and His Family (Box 12)
  - Contents of Box 13: (Box 13)
    - Journals (Box 13)
      Includes Thomas' writings and drawings.
  - Contents of Box 14: (Box 14)
    - Journals (Box 14)
    - Laid in journals: Personal Correspondence Between Thomas and Terri (Box 14)
    - Laid in journals: Foreign Currency (Box 14)
    - Holding Bag for Journal (Box 14)
  - Contents of Box 15: (Box 15)
    - Short Poems by Thomas, [1982-1990] (Box 15)
    - [Instrument Subject Files] (Box 15)
      Articles and notes on the making and functions of different instruments.
    - Wedding Photograph Album (Box 15)
    - Thomas' Address Book (Box 15)
    - Travel Documents (Box 15)
      Includes ticket stubs, currency exchange receipts, etc.
    - Writings and Correspondence Between Thomas and Terri (Box 15)
    - Clippings (Box 15)
  - Contents of Box 16: (Box 16)
    - Slides and Negatives (Box 16)
      Scenes from Africa trip, 1997
    - Photographs and Albums
      - 35th Birthday Party (Box 16)
      - Japan, 1993 (Box 16)
        Includes photographs from Madarzo Festival.
      - Hawaii (Box 16)
  - Contents of Box 17: (Box 17)
    - Photographs from Portugal, Hawaii, Vermont, and New Hampshire (Box 17)
    - Photographs from Spirits Rebellious, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Photographs from the Saratoga Festival in Vermont, Summer 1987 (Box 17)
    - Photographs from the Knitting Factory, 1991 Apr. 11 (Box 17)
  - Contents of Box 18: (Box 18)